crowdfundinginternational.eu 2019-04-24

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
Crowdfunding International takes the privacy of our Members and Project Members seriously. We are
committed to safeguarding your privacy while providing You with our high-quality platform..
Objective and Scope of This Privacy Policy
This Crowdfunding International Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy”) is issued by Crowdfunding
International B.V. for itself and its members (collectively "CFI”, "We”, or "Us”) to explain the data
processing practices of CFI. CFI processes personal data in accordance with the requirements of the
European Union’s Data Protection Directive and the data protection laws and other applicable laws
and regulations of the countries in which We provide services. This Privacy Policy applies to personal
data as defined by the Data Protection Directive and national data protection laws ("Personal Data”)
and to other information that You provide to CFI. This Privacy Policy describes how We collect and
process information provided by You, your right to limit our processing of your information, and your
right to access, correct, and delete your information that We hold. Additional details about our use of
your information with respect to specific CFI services is found in the relevant terms and conditions,
which should be read together with this Privacy Policy.
Your Consent to Use Personal Data
We use your Personal Data only with your consent. You may withhold or withdraw your consent for
CFI to process your Personal Data. Certain Personal Data is required for Us to provide services or
merchandise orders to You or to meet our legal obligations, and your withholding or withdrawal of
consent to use this Personal Data may prevent CFI from providing the services that You have registered
for. Other Personal Data is not required for Us to provide those services to You but is used by Us to
provide You with better levels of service or for marketing and communications as well as other
purposes. Your consent to this use of your Personal Data is optional. We will advise You which Personal
Data You must provide and which is optional. By using CFI’s website and platform, you consent to the
collection of certain information. See ‘How Do We Collect Information?’ below.
1|6               Privacy Policy – last updated 11-11-2016

What Information Do We Collect?
The Personal Data and other information that we process varies depending on your relationship with
CFI. Among the Personal Data and other information that We may collect is the following:
• Name
• Residential address
• Date of birth
• National identification number
• Telephone number
• IP and MAC addresses and browser information
• Email address
• Banking details, credit or debit card information, or other information needed to process payments
to or from You
• Demographic information such as your profession, hobbies, education, gender, ethnicity, and
income. This type of information is never mandatory.
• Other identifying information
Use of Cookies
Cookies are small text files that are sent to your computer so that our websites can remember the
settings and information that you submit. That way You don’t have to re-enter them when You re-visit
a page or visit a new page on the same website. We also use cookies to measure how You use our
websites so that We can make sure that they meet your needs. You can control whether or not your
computer accepts cookies, however, refusing to accept cookies may affect your experience using our
websites. For more information about cookies, please go to the website www.allaboutcookies.org.
How Do We Collect Information?
We collect Personal Data and other information from You in a variety of ways, including:
2|6               Privacy Policy – last updated 11-11-2016

• the submission of Personal Data by You to CFI through our websites ;
• the use of cookies;
• the submission of an online order for CFI services or merchandise orders;
• the submission of a project and donation request;
• when We and You communicate by email, telephone, chat line, or otherwise; and
• provision of your Personal Data to CFI by CFI’s business partners.
CFI will not contact You by telephone or email to request information such as credit card numbers,
account numbers, passwords and pin codes. Do not open or respond to e-mails requesting this type
of information. Please contact CFI if You receive such a request.
How Do We Use Your Personal Data?
CFI processes Personal Data for a variety of purposes, including:
• to verify, process, and administer your registrations for CFI services
• to ensure a secure ordering of merchandise product process
• to maintain our commercial relationship with You
• to analyse, understand, and respond to your service needs
• to improve the products and services that We offer to You and to develop new products and
services
• to meet our legal and regulatory obligations and to protect CFI’s legal and financial interests
(including fraud detection and prevention)
• for the provision of services to our Members and Project Managers and compliance with our
contractual obligations to them
• to facilitate financial, accounting and administrative functions
3|6                 Privacy Policy – last updated 11-11-2016

• to send commercial and marketing communications to You about services and products from CFI
and CFI business partners that We believe may be of interest to you.
We may provide your Personal Data to governmental authorities in response to specific requests
from those authorities or as part of statistical and analytical reports. When information is provided in
statistical or analytical form, information that might specifically identify you will not be disclosed.
How Long Do We Keep Your Personal Data?
CFI keeps your Personal Data as long as it is required for the purposes for which it was initially collected.
In certain situations, We may need to keep your Personal Data for a minimum period to comply with
legal requirements. We do not keep your Personal Data longer than permitted by law.
Where and How Do We Store Your Personal Data?
Your Personal Data is stored by CFI on secure computer servers located in The Netherlands. See
Transfer of Personal Data to Third Parties below. All Personal Data is stored according to industry
standards. See Security below.
Third-Party Sites
CFI’s websites contain links to third-party sites owned or operated by CFI business partners or other
companies. If You use these links, You will leave CFI’s websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to
third-party websites. You should review the privacy disclosures of those websites..
4|6                Privacy Policy – last updated 11-11-2016

Transfer of Personal Data to Third Parties
CFI may transfer your Personal Data to third parties as permitted by this Privacy Policy and applicable
law. CFI transfers Personal Data to third parties only where the third party (a) has provided satisfactory
assurances that it will protect Personal Data consistent with this Privacy Policy; or (b) has signed an
agreement with CFI regarding the transfer of Personal Data in accordance with the Data Protection
Directive; or (c) is located in the European Union or another country which is deemed to provide
adequate protection of Personal Data under the Data Protection Directive;
Security
CFI has implemented technological and organizational measures to safeguard your Personal Data from
unauthorized or improper access during collection and while it is in our possession. Sensitive
information (such as gender, ethnicity, and financial information) is subject to heightened security
measures. You should also take measures to safeguard your Personal Data by maintaining the
confidentiality of your username and password, logging out of CFI’s websites, closing your web
browsers when You have concluded your online activities, and not providing your Personal Data to
persons that are unfamiliar to You.
CFI and You may communicate by email or chat and these communications may at times contain
Personal Information. While it is illegal to intercept or disclose the contents of email and chat
communications, these communications are not secure. We recommend that you do not send
sensitive information, such as financial information, by email or chat, and we will not ask you to provide
this information in this manner.
Your Right to Access Your Personal Data
You have the right to access your Personal Data, to correct your Personal Data if the information that
We have is erroneous, and in some cases to delete your Personal Data. You may obtain a copy or
correct or request deletion of your Personal Data by contacting our Privacy Officer at
info@crowdfundinginternational.eu or by writing to:
Privacy Officer
Crowdfunding International B.V.
Houtstraat 35A
6127 EB Grevenbicht
The Netherlands
5|6               Privacy Policy – last updated 11-11-2016

We may impose reasonable restrictions on requests for access to or to correct your Personal Data
and We may charge You a reasonable fee as permitted by law for provision of your Personal Data. If
you request deletion of your data, We may not be able to provide services to You. We are permitted
to keep certain of your Personal Data in order to meet our legal, financial, audit, and business needs,
even if you request its deletion.
Limitation of Liability
CFI uses reasonable efforts to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy and applicable law regarding
the processing of your Personal Data. Except as provided by applicable law, CFI shall not be responsible
for direct or indirect damages that may result from non-compliance with this Privacy Policy.
Changes to Privacy Policy
CFI may change this Privacy Policy at any time without prior notice. All changes are effective
immediately after they are posted on CFI’s websites.
Version 1.0
Issue Date: 11th November 2016
6|6                Privacy Policy – last updated 11-11-2016
